<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Agapay</string>

    <string name="about">ABOUT</string>
    <string name="Philippines">The PHILIPPINES are an island group of over 7,500 islands;
        the main islands are Luzon, Mindanao, Mindoro, Leyte, Samar, Negros and Panay.
        Most of the Philippine islands are of volcanic origin. The archipelago is
        situated within the Southeast Asian part of the Pacific Ring of Fire, an area
        of intense volcanic and seismic activities. Along the eastern side of the islands
        runs the Philippine Trench, a submarine trench in the floor of the Philippine Sea. The Galathea
        Depth within the underwater canyon is one of the deepest depths of the ocean at
        10,540m (34,580 feet)</string>

    <string name="MSA">Map of Philippines, Maritime Southeast Asia.</string>

    <string name="LVM">The map shows the main island Luzon, Visayas,
        and Mindanao, other large and small islands, regional capitals,
        major cities, main roads, railroads and major airports.</string>
    <string name="mayon">Mt. Mayon a sacred mountain and an active stratovolcano in the province
        of Albay on the islan of Luzon, Philippines.
        Image: Albert Lozado</string>

    <string name="Area">With a total of 300,000 km(2), the country is about the size
        of Italy or slightly larger than the US state of Arizona.</string>

    <string name="Population">A population of nearly 108 million people (in 2020) making
        the Philippines the world\'s 13th most populous country. The nation\'s capital is Manila,
        located on Luzon island within a densely populated conglomerate of several
        other major cities. Together they form Metro Manila, also known as the National
        Capital Region (NCR). 12.8 million people live in Metro Manila. The country\'s spoken
        languages are Filipino (based on Tagalog) and English.</string>

    <string name="PMSA">The map shows the islands of the Philippines in Maritime
        Southeast Asia. The archipelago lies to the east of the South China Sea and
        west of the Philippine Sea and the western Pacific Ocean. Nearby
        countries are Malaysia in the southwest, Indonesia in the south, Vietnam
        in the west, and Taiwan, and mainland China to the north. The Philippines
        shares maritime borders with China, Indonesia, Japan, Malaysia, Palau,
        Taiwan (ROC), and Vietnam.
</string>

</resources>