<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Agapay</string>

    <string name="about">ABOUT</string>
    <string name="Philippines">The PHILIPPINES are an island group of over 7,500 islands;
        the main islands are Luzon, Mindanao, Mindoro, Leyte, Samar, Negros and Panay.
        Most of the Philippine islands are of volcanic origin. The archipelago is
        situated within the Southeast Asian part of the Pacific Ring of Fire, an area
        of intense volcanic and seismic activities. Along the eastern side of the islands
        runs the Philippine Trench, a submarine trench in the floor of the Philippine Sea. The Galathea
        Depth within the underwater canyon is one of the deepest depths of the ocean at
        10,540m (34,580 feet)</string>

    <string name="MSA">Map of Philippines, Maritime Southeast Asia.</string>

    <string name="LVM">The map shows the main island Luzon, Visayas,
        and Mindanao, other large and small islands, regional capitals,
        major cities, main roads, railroads and major airports.</string>
    <string name="mayon">Mt. Mayon a sacred mountain and an active stratovolcano in the province
        of Albay on the islan of Luzon, Philippines.
        Image: Albert Lozado</string>

    <string name="Area">With a total of 300,000 km(2), the country is about the size
        of Italy or slightly larger than the US state of Arizona.</string>

    <string name="Population">A population of nearly 108 million people (in 2020) making
        the Philippines the world\'s 13th most populous country. The nation\'s capital is Manila,
        located on Luzon island within a densely populated conglomerate of several
        other major cities. Together they form Metro Manila, also known as the National
        Capital Region (NCR). 12.8 million people live in Metro Manila. The country\'s spoken
        languages are Filipino (based on Tagalog) and English.</string>

    <string name="PMSA">The map shows the islands of the Philippines in Maritime
        Southeast Asia. The archipelago lies to the east of the South China Sea and
        west of the Philippine Sea and the western Pacific Ocean. Nearby
        countries are Malaysia in the southwest, Indonesia in the south, Vietnam
        in the west, and Taiwan, and mainland China to the north. The Philippines
        shares maritime borders with China, Indonesia, Japan, Malaysia, Palau,
        Taiwan (ROC), and Vietnam.
    </string>

    <string name="landforms">LANDFORMS - Natural formation of rocks, soil and even dirt
        found on earth. They come in different shapes and sizes.</string>

    <string name="landforms1">- Theses place are also the tourist spot that foreigners
        and even filipino visit during summer.</string>

    <string name="mountain">- It is a place that is much higher than the
        land around it. Some mountains very steep and around to climb.</string>

    <string name="apo">- At 2,956 meters above sea level, Mt. Apo (or "master" or
        "grandchild" in Filipino) is the highest mountain in the Philippines. Scale
        the summit and be rewarded with majestic views of Davao to the northeast,
        Digos City to the southeast, and Kidapawan to the West.</string>

    <string name="apo1">- MT. APO was declared a national park in 1934 by then PRESIDENT
        MANUEL L. QUEZON, and rightly so. Apart from lush forests, it is home
        to over 272 bird species, the most notable of which is the endangered
        Philippine eagle.</string>

    <string name="dulang">- The second highest mountain the Philippines is home to the
        Talaandig tribe, who consider Mt. Dulang-Dulang a sacred place.</string>

    <string name="dulang1">- The tribes folk live side by side with an amazing variety
        of wildlife - deer, flying lemurs, monkeys, and bats, to name a few.</string>

    <string name="dulang2">- Start your journey on trails lined with pine trees and then
        navigate through jungles that take you back in time. Be rewarded with a view of
        Mt. Apo and the entire Kitanglad range at the peak.</string>

    <string name="pulag">- MT.PULAG is Luzon\'s highest peak. This national park is home
        to the Ibalos, Kilanguya, Kankana-eys, Karao, Ifugaos, and the Ilocanos.</string>

    <string name="pulag1">- It is a popular destination among mountaineers for its amazing
        sea of clouds and views of the Milky Way galaxy right before the sun rises.</string>

    <string name="pulag2">- Due to a fire that destroyed more than 5 hectares of grassland,
        Mt. Pulag is closed to trekkers until further  notice.</string>

    <string name="kitanglad">- Legend has it that Mt.Kitanglad was named after a great
        flood submerged the land and only the mountain\'s peak, which was the size of a blade
        of lemon grass (TANGLAD in Filipino) was visible.</string>

    <string name="kitanglad1">- Mountaineers might be surprised to learn that Mt.Kitanglad
        is a communications center. But don\'t be put off by its seeming modernity. The
        challenging trails, beautiful views, and the richness of its biodiversity make the journey
        worth it.</string>

    <string name="tabayoc">- Tabayoc, in the native tongue, means (BASIN), which may refer
        to the four lakes surrounding it: Lake Tabeo, Ambulalakao, Iculus, and Detapnaco.</string>

    <string name="tabayoc1">- A significant portion of Mt. Tabayoc’s trail is known as the
        “Monkey Trail” – trekkers would have to climb over boulders, swing from one branch
        to another, and hang on to vines to move forward.</string>

    <string name="tabayoc2">- If you’ve ever wondered what it would be like to be in Tarzan’s
        shoes (or, um, loincloth), climbing the second highest mountain in Luzon would be your
        chance to find out.</string>

    <string name="kalatungan">- Mt. Kalatungan (or “praying mantis eggs” in the native tongue)
        is classified as a potentially active volcano and is considered as one of the most
        challenging climbs in the country. In keeping with local traditions, mountaineers
        perform a ritual sacrifice prior to the climb.</string>

    <string name="piapayungan">- Mt. Piapayungan remains to be one of Mindanao\'s most elusive peaks</string>

    <string name="ragang">- Mt. Ragang, also known as the Blue Mountain, is the highest
        point in Lanao Del Sur. Emerge from the ethereal mossy forest and be rewarded with
        a view of Lake Lanao as well as towns of Maguindanao, Lanao del Sur, and Cotabato.</string>

    <string name="maagnaw">- Mt.Maagnaw is the third highest peak in the Kitanglad range
        and the 8th highest mountain in the country. If you\'ve conquered Mt.Dulang-Dulang and
        Mt.Kitanglad, this should also be on your list. The views at the summit are truly
        breathtaking.</string>

    <string name="timbak">- If you\'re on a mission to summit the 10 highest mountains
        in the Philippines, Mt.Timbak - 9th on the list - said to be the easiest to complete.</string>

    <string name="timbak1">- Get a glimpse of the local way of life along the way, and take
        photos of the three crosses at the summit. Mountaineers usually plan a day
        hike to Mt.Timbak from Baguio. Its environs are also a playground for trail runners.</string>


    <string name="volcano">- It is a landform that has a small opening on top where hot
        rocks or lava come out when it erupts.</string>

    <string name="volcano1">- VOLCANOES in the Philippines, (15 in CENTRAL
        PHILIPPINES) ALTO, BILIRAN, CABALIAN, CANCAJANG, CANLAON, CUERNOS DE NEGROS,
        HINGATUNGAN, ILIHAN, LOBI, MAHAGNAO, MANDALAGAN, MARIPIPI, NELANGAAPAN, PACDAHAUAN,
        SILAY. (33 in LUZON ISLAND) AMBALATUNGAN, AMORONG, ANILAO HILL, ARAYAT, BANAHAW, BINULUAN,
        BULUSAN, CAGUA, CARILAO, CONE-CULASI, CORREGIDOR, DAGIT-DAGITAN, GATE MOUNTAINS,
        IRIGA, ISAROG, LABO, LAGUNA, MAKILING, MALEPUNYO, MALINAO, MALINDIG, MARIVELES,
        MASARAGA, MAYON, NATIB, PANAY, PATOC, PINATUBO, POCDOL MOUNATINS, SAN PABLO,
        SANGAY, SANTO TOMAS, TAAL. (20 in MINDANAO) AMPIRO, APO, BALATUKAN, BALUT,
        BLIT, HIBOK-HIBOK, IMBING, KALADIS, KALATUNGAN, KITABUD, LATUKAN, LEONARD RANGE,
        MAKATURING, MALINDANG, MATUTUM, MUSUAN, PACO, PARKER, QUEZON, RAGANG. (6 in NORTH LUZON)
        BABUYAN CLARO, CAMIGUIN DE BABUYANES, DIDICAS, IRAYA, MATAREM. (1 in SULU ISLAND)
        JOLO.</string>

    <string name="volcano2">- There are 53 active volcanoes in the Philippines. The
        Philippines belong to the Pacific Ring of Fire where the oceanic Philippine plate
        and several smaller microplates are subducting along the Philippines Trench
        to the E, and the Luzon, Sulu and several other small Trenches to the W.</string>

    <string name="volcano3">According to the Philippine Institute of Volcanology and Seismology
        (PHIVOLCS),at least 24 of these volcanoes are active or potentially active, while
        the rest are dormant. Based on documented eruptions over the years, the six most
        active volcanoes are:</string>

    <string name="plain">- It is low, flat and wide landform. It has many towns and
        cities and it is where most people build their houses. This is suitable for
        planting various crops like rice and corn. usually, people build their homes
        and establish settlements with governing bodies in the plain. The widest plain is
        in Central Luzon. It is otherwise known as the Rice Granary of the country. In
        the Visayas, the plains of Panay and Negros are bountiful. in Mindanao, the
        wide plains are found in Cotabato, Davao, and Agusan.</string>

    <string name="plain1">- There are 10 biggest islands in the Philippines. These
        are the following: Luzon, Mindanao, Samar, Negros, Palawan, Panay, Mindoro,
        Leyte, Cebu, and Bohol.</string>

    <string name="plain2">* CENTRAL LUZON region, also known as Region 3, comprises the
        largest plain of the Philippines, it is called most of the country\'s rice supply. It
        was the third largest region in terms of population size amidst the 16 regions
        in the Philippines, containing 10.50 percent of the 76.5 million human beings of the
        country as recorded in Census 2000.</string>

    <string name="hill">- It is lower and smaller than a mountain. It is easier to
        climb than a mountain.</string>

    <string name="banati">- It is a hill located in Bool, Tagbilaran City. This hill
        commands a scenic view overlooking vast Bohol Sea, Islands of Mindanao,
        Negros and Siquijor and the strait of Panglao Island. Elevation is 146 above sea level.</string>

    <string name="bangan">- It is a protected area of the Philippines located in
        the municipality of Bayombong, Nueva Vizcaya in Cagayan Valley. The park
        covers an area of 13.90 hectares. It was declared a national park in 1995
        by virtue of Republic Act No. 7954.</string>

    <string name="bangan1">- The park is a historic and cultural landmark of Nueva
        Viscaya, being the site of the first mass in the province in the province in
        1739 officiated by Father Pedro Freire. The event also marked the founding
        of the municipality of Bayombong. The park is also the site of the annual
        "Stations of the Cross" staged by the local Catholic church during the Lenten
        season using live actors depicting the last moments leading to Jesus Christ\'s
        crucifixion. It is also an ideal year-round destination for hiking enthusiasts
        with the observation deck commanding a great view of the expanse of the surrounding
        valley formed by the Caraballo and Cordillera Central mountains.</string>

    <string name="cassamata">- It is a protected area of the Philippines located in the
        municipality of Bangued, Abra in te Cordillera Administrative Region. The park
        covers an area of 57 hectares (140 acres) and was declared a protected area in
        1974.</string>

    <string name="cassamata1">- Its location in the southern limits of Bangued municipality
        by the Ilocos Sur-Abra road affords easy access to its residents. The hill itself
        is an easy climb via a winding road or on foot by concrete stairways. Visitors
        are rewarded with panoramic views of the small town below as well as the whole
        expanse of the Abra River valley flanked by the Cordillera Central and Ilocos
        mountain ranges. The 990-meter (3,248 feet) tall Mount Banti Goolong (also
        called SLEEPING BEAUTY mountain by locals) is especially impresive from Victoria
        Park located in the summit of the hill. In addition to the park and mountain
        trails, Cassamata Hill also provides recreational facilities such as swimming
        pool, a hotel and an amphitheater. The park is also the site of a water reservoir
        and a shrine to the Virgin Mary.</string>

    <string name="chocolate">- Are a geological formation in the Bohol province of the
        Philippines. There are at least 1,260 hills but there may be as many as 1,776
        hills spread over an area of more than 50 square kilometers (20 sq mi). They
        are covered in green grass that turns brown during the dry season, hence the name.</string>

    <string name="chocolate1">- The CHOCOLATE HILLS is a famous tourist attraction
        of Bohol. They are featured in the provincial flag and seal to symbolize the
        abundance of natural attractions in the province. They are in the Philippine
        Tourism Authority\'s list of tourist destination in the Philippines; they have
        been declared the country\'s third National Geological Monument and proposed for
        inclusion in the UNESCO World Heritage.</string>

    <string name="himontagon">- Are a group of hills in Loay, Bohol, Philippines,
        about 20 kilometers from the Tagbilaran City.</string>

    <string name="lignon">- It is a prominent hill in the city of Legazpi, some
        3 kilometers west of its downtown port area in Albay, Philippines. The
        summit rises to about 512 feet (156 meters), overlooking the Mayon Volcano
        to the northwest and the entire city and Albay Gulf to the east. The whole
        site is managed by the city and provincial government, and has been designed
        as a Nature Park.</string>

    <string name="lignon1">- Lignon hill is a prehistoric cinder cone near the foot
        of Mayon, ssome 12 kilometers south-southeast of the volcano\'s summit. It is
        mainly composed of dolerite and basaltic volcanic rocks. Except for Mayon
        Volcano, it is the highest point in the city situated next to the Legazpi
        Airport in barangay 41 (Bogtong) near the city\'s border with the municipality
        of Daraga. It hosts the Mayon Volcano Observatory, the central monitoring
        station of the Philippine Institute of Volcanology and Seismology built in 1989.</string>

    <string name="manduyog">- It is a religious sanctuary located at the Aklan State
        University, Banga, Aklan, the Philippines. Today, Manduyog Hill attracts visitors
        not only within the province but even from other provinces in the country.
        During fiesta day every September 14 and the Lenten season, throngs of
        multitudes go up the Hill not only the religious fervor, but also by the
        captivating spell of its magical tranquility.</string>

    <string name="pedro">- Also known as PC Hill or Tantawan, is a hill in Cotabato
        City, Philippines.</string>

    <string name="pedro1">- The name of hill, Pedro Colin Hill was named after Peter
        the Apostle (or San Pedro) by the Spaniards in the 1800s, during the time when
        the Spanish began exploring South Central Mindanao. COLINA means hill in Spanish,
        hence Pedro Colina Hill\'s name is tautological or redundant. The hill is also
        traditionally known as Tantawan, which meanas EXTENSIVE VEIW.</string>

    <string name="plateau">- A plateau is a flat stretch of land on top os a mountain.
        This suitable for tending animals as the temperature here is cool. It is also
        ideal for plants that do not need much water. The bid plateaus around the country
        are found in the Mountain Province, Benguet, Ifugao, and Kalinga-Apayao in Luzon.</string>

    <string name="mountainranges">- It is a chain of mountains bondered by higlands
        or separated from other mountains by passes or valleys.</string>

    <string name="apotalomo">- Also known as Mount Talomo) or Talomo Mountain Range
        is a mountain Range located in the province of Davao del Sur and Cotabato in
        the island of Mindanao Philippines. The highest peak on the range is Mount Apo
        9,692 ft. (2,954 m) it is the highest mountain in the Philippines. Mount Talomo 8,773 ft
        (2,674 m) is one of the top 15 highest mountain in the Philippines. In terms of climbing
        difficulty, it is rated with a 7/9 difficulty and has a 2-4 trail class.</string>

    <string name="caraballo">- It is a mountain range in the central part of Luzon island
        in the Philippines, situated between the Cordillera Central and Sierra Madre
        mountain ranges. The mountains serve as the location off the headways of the
        Cagayan River, the longest in the country.</string>

    <string name="central">- It is the longest and largest mountain range in the island
        of Panay and Western Visayas in the Philippines. With a total lenght of 170 km (105 miles)
        long north-south and 34 km (21 miles) width east-west. It is famous for its
        diverse flora and fauna. Located through the western Panay, started from Ibajay, Aklan
        to the north and Aniniy, Antique southern tip to the south.</string>

    <string name="peninsula">- A peninsula is a substantial portion of land that extends
        from the mainland and has water on three sides. It can be formed by rising or
        falling sea level that may expose or cover portions of land to form a peninsula.
        An uplift or fall of landmass may also help to form a peninsula. A separation
        of Landmasses over millions of years can create a peninsula.</string>

    <string name="bataan">- The peninsula faces the South china Sea to the west and
        Subic Bay to the north-west, and encloses Manila Bay to the east.</string>

    <string name="bondoc">- commonly known as BONPEN, is located in the southeastern
        part of Quezon Province in Calabarzon Region, southern part of Luzon Island,
        Philippines. The peninsula consists of 12 municipalities.</string>

    <string name="calatagan">- Calatagan comprises the Calatagan Peninsula between the
        South China Sea and Balayan Bay. The peninsula\'s near white sand beaches are
        well known vacation and leisures sites. The word CALATAGAN is taken from the
        Tagalog word LATAG and is closely associated with KAPATAGAN, which means a vast portion
        of flat and lying between the hills and mountais.</string>

    <string name="valley">- It is a type landform. A valley is a lower part in the land,
        between two higher parts which might be hills or mountains. Valleys often start as a
        downward fold between two upwards folds in the surface of the Earth, and sometimes
        as a rift valley.</string>

    <string name="valley1">- A valley is made deeper by a stream of water or a river
        as it flows from the high land to the lower land, and into a lake or sea. Some
        valleys are made by GLACIERS  which are slow-moving rivers of ice.</string>

    <string name="allah">- It is a large valley of the Allah River in the provinces of
        South Cotabato and Sultan Kudarat on the island of Mindanao, Philippines. It
        is formed by the Roxas-Matulas Range in the north and the Daguma Mountain Range
        in the south.</string>

    <string name="cagayan">- Cagayan Valley is the second largest Philippine administrative
        region by land area. Most of the land area is situated on the valley between the Cordilleras
        and the Sierra Madre mountain ranges. The eponymous Cagayan River, the country\'s
        largest and second longest, runs through the region and flows from the Caraballo
        Mountains and ends at Aparri.</string>

    <string name="davao">- The province was formerly known as COMPOSTELA VALLEY, from
        its inception until December 2019, when a plebiscite ratified the law that
        proposed to rename the province to Davao de Oro.</string>

    <string name="dewil">- located in the northernmost part of Palawan, an island province
        of the Philippines that is located in the Mimaropa region, is an archaeological site
        composed of thousands of artifacts and features.</string>

    <string name="population">In statistics, a population is the entire pool from which a
        statistical sample is drawn. A population may refer to an entire group of people,
        objects, events, hospital visits, or measurements. A population can thus be said
        to be an aggregate observation of subjects grouped together by a common feature.</string>

    <string name="population1">A population can be defined by any number of characteristics
        within a group that statisticians use to draw conclusions about the subjects in
        a study. A population can be vague or specific. Examples of population
        (defined VAGUELY) include the number of newborn babies in North America,
        total number of tech startups in Asia, average height of all CFA candidates
        in the world, mean weight of U.S taxpayers and so on.</string>

    <string name="ph">- The current population of the PHILIPPINES is 110,416,174
        as of Thursday, January 28, 2021, based on Worldometer elaboration of the
        latest United Nations data.</string>

    <string name="ph1">- The Philippines 2020 poulation is estimated at 109,581,078
        people at mid year according to UN data.</string>

    <string name="ph2">- The Philippines population is equavalent to 1.41% of
        the total world population.</string>

    <string name="ph3">- The Philippines ranks number 13 in the list of countries
        (and dependencies) by population.</string>

    <string name="ph4">- The population density in the Philippines is 368 per Km2
        (952 people per mi2).</string>
    <string name="ph5">- The total land area is 298,170 Km2 (115,124 sq. miles).</string>
    <string name="ph6">- 47.5% of the population is urban (52,008,603 people i 2020).</string>
    <string name="ph7">- The median age in the Philippines is 25.7 years.</string>

    <string name="pdc">The Philippines is not a developed country. The nation falls
        behind on every one of the most common metrics used by economist to determine
        development status. The Philippines\' per capita gross domestic product (GDP),
        Human Development Index (HDI) and life expectancy sit well below the thresholds
        for developed country status. Moreover, the country\'s infant mortality rate is
        very high, its industrialization is minimal, and many of its citizens lack
        access to quality health care and higher education.</string>

    <string name="pdc1">As of 2016, per capita GDP in the Philippines is $7,358, well below
        any accepted minimum for developed country status. The country\'s latest HDI is
        0.66. Its infant mortality rate 22 per 1,000 live births and its life expectancy
        is 69 years.</string>

    <string name="pdc2">The Philippines is very much a developing country, and it has a
        long way to go to reach developed status.</string>

    <string name="manufacturing">- MANUFACTURING comprises more than half of the Philippine\'s
        industrial sector and accounts for almost a quarter of the country\'s Gross
        Domestic Product (GDP). From an annual growth rate of 5.4 in 2012, the
        manufacturing sector grew by 10.5 in 2013 and 8.1 in 2014</string>

    <string name="tourism">TOURISM is an important sector for Philippine economy. In
        2019, the travel and tourism industry contributed 12.7% to the country\'s GDP.
        Philippines is an archipelagic country composed of 7,641 islands with 82 provinces
        divided in 17 regions.</string>

    <string name="bpo">As a prime knowledge process outsourcing destination, the Philippines
        KPO sector thrives and stays as part of the country\'s major contributor
        to its GDP. In fact, as per the Information Technology and Business Process Management
        (IT-BPM) road map 2022, the demand for mid-skill and high-skill jobs will take
        46 and 27 of IT-BPM careers, respectively. This proves there is more to
        come for the future of the knowledge process outsourcing industry.</string>

    <string name="infrastructure">The logistics industry remains a significant and growing segment
        of the Philippine economy due to commerce and infrastructure developments.
        In 2019, the transportation and storage summed up to USD 13 billion and has accounted
        for around 4% of the Philippines\' GDP over the last five years.</string>

    <string name="agribusiness">AGRIBUSINESS refers to agriculture-related activities that
        put farmers, processors, distributors, and consumers within a system that produces,
        transport, markets, and distributes agricultural products.</string>

    <string name="philippines">- Is an archipelagic country in Southeast Asia. Situated
        in the western Pacific Ocean, it consists of about 7,641 islands that are
        broadly categorized under three main geographical divisions from north to
        south: Luzon, Visayas, Mindanao. The capital city of the Philippines is
        MANILA and the most populous city is QUEZON CITY, both within the single
        urban area of Metro Manila.</string>
    <string name="philippines1">- The Philippines\' position as an island country on the
        Pacific RING OF FIRE and close to the equator makes the country prone to earthquakes
        and typhoons. The country has a variety of natural resources and a globally significant
        level of biodiversity. The Philippines has an area of around 300,000 km2
        (120,000 sq mi) with a population of around 109 million people. As of 2020,
        it is the 8th-most populated country in the world. Multiple ethnicities and
        cultures are found throughout the islands.</string>

    <string name="flag">- National flag consisting of horizontal stripes of blue and red with
        a white hoist triangle incorporating a golden sun and three stars. The flag\'s width-to-length
        ratio is generally 1 to 2.</string>

    <string name="flag1">- The 1898 overthrow of Spanish authority by the United
        States led Filipinos to believe that their country’s independence,
        proclaimed on June 12, 1898, was guaranteed.A national flag quite different from the revolutionary
        banners used a few years before was adopted. At the hoist was a white
        triangle, symbolic of liberty and probably derived from Masonic
        symbolism.  </string>

    <string name="flag2">- It bore a golden sun and three golden stars, standing for
        the three main areas in the Philippines—the Luzon group of islands in
        the north, the Visayan group in the south, and the main southern island
        of Mindanao. The eight sun rays were for the provinces where the
        original anti-Spanish revolt had broken out. The remainder of the flag
        consisted of horizontal stripes of blue (for the willingness to
        sacrifice oneself for freedom) over red (for courage).</string>

    <string name="coat">- THE COAT OF ARMS OF THE PHILIPPINES, features the eight-rayed
        sun of the Philippines with each ray representing the eight provinces
        (Batangas, Bulacan, Cavite, Manila,Laguna, Nueva Ecija, Pampanga, and Tarlac) </string>

    <string name="coat1">- Which were placed under martial law by Governor-General
        Ramon Blanco during the Philippine Revolution, and the three five pointed
        stars representing the three major island groups of Luzon, the Visayas,
        and Mindanao.</string>

    <string name="anthem">- The Philippine National Anthem is a product of revolution,
        a response to the need of the revolutionary times that gave birth to it.
        And this need arose in 1898, when the revolution against Spain was in it its
        second year and a Filipino victory was in sight.</string>
    <string name="anthem1">- Gen. Emilio Aguinaldo astutely recognized the need
        for national symbols to rally the nation against the enemy. On June 5,
        1898, he commissioned Julian Felipe , a Cavite pianist and composer, to
        work on a march for the revolutionists. Felipe worked on the assignment
        for six days and on June 11, sitting in front of a piano in the Aguinaldo
        living room, played his music before the presidente and his lieutenants.
        Named by Felipe the Marcha Filipino Magdalo (after Aguinaldo\'s nom de
        guerre and his faction in the Katipunan), the music was adopted on the
        spot and renamed the Marcha Nacional Filipina (Philippine National March)
        .</string>

    <string name="anthem2">- The national anthem was heard publicly for the first
        time on June 12, 1898, when, standing on the balcony of his Kawit mansion,
        Aguinaldo proclaimed Asia\'s first independent republic before a cheering
        throng. Two rallying symbols were presented to the infant nation that day.
        Also displayed for the first time was the national flag, unfurled to th
        e stirring strains of the marcha nacional played by the band of San
        Francisco de Malabon (now Heneral Trias) whose members had learned the
        music the day before.</string>

    <string name="nationalism">The Aguinaldo Shrine built in 1845 is where Philippine
        independence from Spain was declared on June 12, 1898.</string>

    <string name="nationalism1">- FILIPINO NATIONALISM, refers to the awakening
        and support of a political identity associated with modern Philippines
        leading to a wide-ranging campaign for political, social, and economic
        freedom in the Philippines.</string>

    <string name="nationalism2">- This gradually emerged out of various political
        and armed movements throughout most of the Spanish East Indies—but
        which has long been fragmented and inconsistent with contemporary
        definitions of such nationalism—as a consequence of more than three
        centuries of Spanish rule.</string>

    <string name="nationalism3">- These movements are characterized by the
        upsurge of anti-colonialist sentiments and ideals which peaked in
        the late 19th century led mostly by the ilustrado or landed, educated
        elites, whether peninsulares, insulares, or native (Indio). This
        served as the backbone of the first nationalist revolution in Asia,
        the Philippine Revolution of 1896. The modern concept would
        later be fully actualized upon the inception of a Philippine state
        with its contemporary borders after being granted independence by
        the United States by the 1946 Treaty of Manila.</string>

    <string name="nationalism4">- The term "Filipino" originally referred to the
        Spanish criollos of the Philippines. During their 333-year rule of the
        Philippines, the Spanish rulers referred the natives as indios.</string>

    <string name="nationalism5">- Also during the colonial era, the Spaniards born
        in the Philippines, who were more known as insulares, criollos, or Creoles,
        were also called "Filipinos." Spanish-born Spaniards or mainland Spaniards
        residing in the Philippines were referred to as Peninsulares. Those of mixed
        ancestry were referred to as Mestizos. The Creoles, despite being regarded
        by the Peninsulares as inferior to them, had enjoyed various government and
        church positions, and composed the majority of the government bureaucracy.
    </string>

    <string name="nationalism6">-  These factors contributed to the birth of the Filipino
        Nationalism.</string>

    <string name="economy">- The decline of Galleon trade between Manila and Acapulco was
        caused by the arrival of the ship Buen Consejo in 1765. The Buen Consejo
        took the shorter route via Cape of Good Hope, a rocky headland on the
        Atlantic coast controlled by Portugal.</string>

    <string name="education">- During the administration of Governor-General Jose
        Raon, a royal order from Spain, which stated that every village or barrio
        must have a school and a teacher, was implemented. The implementation of
        the order expanded the reach of basic education during the Spanish era.
        Also, during the 18th century, modern agricultural tools made many people
        leave farming for pursuing academic and intellectual courses. After the
        arrival of Buen Consejo, the Philippines had more direct contact to Europe
        and the ideas circulating. Thus, the Philippines was influenced by the
        principles during the Age of Enlightenment and radical changes during the
        French Revolution.</string>

    <string name="secularization">- By royal decree on February 27, 1767, King Carlos III
        ordered the Jesuits to be expelled from Spain, and from all her colonies.
        The decree reached the Philippines in early 1768, wherein Governor-General
        Raon tried to do the Jesuits a favor by delaying the implementation of the
        royal order in exchange of bribes. This gave the Jesuit priests to hide
        all of their possessions and destroy documents that could be held against
        them, which were supposed to be confiscated. The first batch of Jesuits,
        numbered 64, left Manila only by May 17, 1768. This event caused Raon
        to face prosecution from the next Governor-General, as ordered by the
        King of Spain. Raon died before the judgment for him was laid.</string>

    <string name="asia">GEOGRAPHY OF ASIA, reviews geographical concepts of classifying
        Asia, the central and eastern part of Eurasia, comprising approximately
        fifty countries.</string>

    <string name="asia1">- The land mass of Asia is not the sum of the land masses
        of each of its regions, which have been defined independently of the whole.
        For example, the borders of Central Asia and the Middle East depend on
        is defining them and for what purpose. These varying definitions are not
        generally reflected in the map of Asia as a whole; for example, Egypt is
        typically included in the Middle East, but not in Asia, even though the
        Middle East is a division of Asia.</string>
    <string name="asia2">- Asia, the world’s largest and most diverse continent. It
        occupies the eastern four-fifths of the giant Eurasian landmass. Asia is more
        a geographic term than a homogeneous continent, and the use of the term to
        describe such a vast area always carries the potential of obscuring the
        enormous diversity among the regions it encompasses. Asia has both the highest
        and the lowest points on the surface of Earth, has the longest coastline of
        any continent, is subject overall to the world\’s widest climatic extremes,
        and, consequently, produces the most varied forms of vegetation and animal
        life on Earth. In addition, the peoples of Asia have established the broadest
        variety of human adaptation found on any of the continents.</string>

    <string name="asia3">- The name Asia is ancient, and its origin has been variously
        explained. The Greeks used it to designate the lands situated to the east of
        their homeland. It is believed that the name may be derived from the Assyrian
        word asu, meaning “east.” Another possible explanation is that it was
        originally a local name given to the plains of Ephesus, which ancient Greeks
        and Romans extended to refer first to Anatolia (contemporary Asia Minor,
        which is the western extreme of mainland Asia), and then to the known world
        east of the Mediterranean Sea. When Western explorers reached South and
        East Asia in early modern times, they extended that label to the whole of
        the immense landmass.</string>

    <string name="history">- Asia was the home of some of the world\'s oldest civilizations.
        The empires of Sumer, Babylonia, Assyria, Media, and Persia and the
        civilizations of Islam flourished in SW Asia, while in the east the
        ancient civilizations of India, China, and Japan prospered. Later,
        nomadic tribes (Huns, Mongols, and Turks) in N and central Asia
        established great empires and gave rise to great westward migration.
        Their tribal, military-state organizations reached their highest form in
        the 13th–14th cent. under the Mongols, whose court was visited by early
        European travelers, notably the Italian Marco Polo.</string>

    <string name="history1">- The Portuguese explorer Vasco da Gama reached India
        by sea in 1498, beginning the era of European imperialism in Asia. In N
        Asia Russian Cossacks crossed Siberia and reached the Pacific by 1640.
        With the formation of English, French, Dutch, and Portuguese trading
        companies in the 17th cent., great trade rivalry developed along the
        coasts of India, SE Asia, and China and resulted in increasing European
        control of Asian lands. By exploiting local disputes and utilizing a
        technological edge brought on by the industrial revolution, European
        powers extended political control over first the Indian subcontinent,
        then SW and SE Asia. European pressure opened China and Japan to trade.
        World War I led to a weakening of European stature in Asia, and the
        Wilson doctrine of self-determination inspired many nationalist and
        revolutionary movements.</string>

    <string name="culture">- Asian refers to all the people who are residing in
        Asia. There are many countries that form a part of the continent of Asia
        like the Islamic nations and the Southeastern countries of Nepal, India
        and Bangladesh. Asia has the largest land mass in the whole world and
        is a home to a majority of human population that is residing in the
        world. Most of the densely populated countries of the world are situated
        in Asia. There are a large number of countries that constitute this
        continent and as a result it is home to a wide variety of cultures and
        traditions. People of Asia are very strongly attached to their homelands
        and find it very painful to separate from their native countries.</string>

    <string name="culture1">- Asian people are progenies of an umpteen number of
        ethnic races. It contains countries like India, Pakistan, Myanmar, China,
        Bangladesh, Afghanistan, Nepal, Sri Lanka and the developed countries of
        Japan and Russia. This continent is abounding with a variety of climates,
        lands and amazing landscapes. From Himalayas to the arid lands of Mongolia
        and Afghanistan, the continent of Asia is bestowed with amazing
        landscapes. Asia has a huge area of land and the western part of Asia
        comprises Muslim countries like UAE, Qatar, Iraq, Iran and Dubai and
        contains features of Arab and Iranian cultures. Asia has people
        following all the religions from Hinduism, Islam and Christianity.
        The continent of Asia is blessed with fertile lands in China and India
        and excels in agricultural production of food grains and rice.</string>

    <string name="culture2">- Asian people are known all over the world for their
        strong cultural values and intelligent minds. This continent has given
        birth to many famous scientists, celebrities and politicians. Although
        this continent does not boast of many developed countries, many
        developing countries within this continent are on the threshold of
        becoming developed. Asia as a continent was initially under the colonial
        rule for a very long time except for the countries of Japan or Russia.
        Many nations like India, China, Pakistan and Afghanistan have suffered
        the brunt of oppressive colonial rule by Europeans and Americans for a
        very long period of time.</string>

    <string name="culture3">- Asia is well known for celebrations and festivals.
        It is a land where festivals of different cultures and religions are
        being celebrated. Among the major Hindu festivals are Diwali, Holi,
        Baisakhi, and Eid ul-Fitr, Dusshera, Onam and Christmas and are
        celebrated with great fervor all over India.</string>

    <string name="world">World history or global history as a field of historical
        study examines history from a global perspective. It emerged centuries
        ago; leading practitioners have included Voltaire (1694-1778), Hegel
        (1770-1831), Karl Marx (1818-1883) and Arnold J. Toynbee (1889-1975).
        The field became much more active (in terms of university teaching, text
        books, scholarly journals, and academic associations) in the late 20th
        century. It is not to be confused with comparative history, which, like
        world history, deals with the history of multiple cultures and nations,
        but does not do so on a global scale. World history looks for common
        patterns that emerge across all cultures. World historians use a thematic
        approach, with two major focal points: integration (how processes of
        world history have drawn people of the world together) and difference
        (how patterns of world history reveal the diversity of the human
        experience).</string>

    <string name="world1">- Jerry H. Bentley has observed that \'the term world
        history has never been a clear signifier with a stable referent\', and
        that usage of the term overlaps with universal history, comparative
        history, global history, big history, macro history, and transnational
        history, among others.</string>

    <string name="world2">- The advent of world history as a distinct academic
        field of study can be traced to the 1960s, but the pace quickened in the
        1980s. A key step was the creation of the World History Association and
        graduate programs at a handful of universities. Over the next decades
        scholarly publications, professional and academic organizations, and
        graduate programs in World History proliferated. World History has often
        displaced Western Civilization in the required curriculum of American high
        schools and universities, and is supported by new textbooks with a world
        history approach.</string>

    <string name="world3">- World History attempts to recognize and address two
        structures that have profoundly shaped professional history-writing:
    </string>

    <string name="world4">- Thus World History tends to study networks, connections,
        and systems that cross traditional boundaries of historical study like
        linguistic, cultural, and national borders. World History is often
        concerned to explore social dynamics that have led to large-scale changes
        in human society, such as industrialization and the spread of capitalism,
        and to analyse how large-scale changes like these have affected different
        parts of the world. Like other branches of history-writing in the second
        half of the twentieth century, World History has a scope far beyond
        historians\' traditional focus on politics, wars, and diplomacy, taking
        in a panoply of subjects like gender history, social history, cultural
        history, and environmental history.</string>

    <string name="org">-The H-World website and online network is used among some
        practitioners of world history, and allows discussions among scholars,
        announcements, syllabi, bibliographies and book reviews. </string>

    <string name="org1">- The International Society for the Comparative Study of
        Civilizations (ISCSC) approaches world history from the standpoint of
        comparative civilizations. Founded at a conference in 1961 in Salzburg,
        Austria, that was attended by Othmar Anderlie, Pitirim Sorokin, and
        Arnold J. Toynbee, this is an international association of scholars that
        publishes a journal, Comparative Civilization Review, and hosts an annual
        meeting in cities around the world.</string>

    <string name="org2">- The Journal of Global History is a scholarly journal
        established in 2006 and is published by Cambridge University Press.
    </string>

    <string name="org3">- The World History Association (WHA) was established in
        1982, and is predominantly an American phenomenon. Since 1990, it
        publishes the Journal of World History on a quarterly basis.</string>

    <string name="pre">- In Ancient China, Chinese world history, that of
        China and the surrounding people of East Asia, was based on the dynastic
        cycle articulated by Sima Qian in circa 100 BC. Sima Qian\'s model is
        based on the Mandate of Heaven. Rulers rise when they united China,
        then are overthrown when a ruling dynasty became corrupt. Each new
        dynasty begins virtuous and strong, but then decays, provoking the
        transfer of Heaven\'s mandate to a new ruler. The test of virtue in a new
        is success in being obeyed by China and neighboring barbarians. After
        2000 years Sima Qian\'s model still dominates scholarship, although the
        dynastic cycle is no longer used for modern Chinese history.</string>


    <string name="early">- During the Renaissance in Europe, history was written
        about states or nations. The study of history changed during the
        Enlightenment and Romanticism. Voltaire described the history of certain
        ages that he considered important, rather than describing events in
        chronological order. History became an independent discipline. It was
        not called philosophia historiae anymore, but merely history (historia).
        Voltaire, in the 18th century, attempted to revolutionize the study of
        world history. First, Voltaire concluded that the traditional study of
        history was flawed. The Christian Church, one of the most powerful
        entities in his time, had presented a framework for studying history.
        Voltaire, when writing History of Charles XII (1731) and The Age of Louis
        XIV (1751), instead choose to focus economics, politics and culture.
        These aspects of history were mostly unexplored by his contemporaries
        and would each develop into their own sections of world history. Above
        all else, Voltaire regarded truth as the most essential part of recording
        world history. Nationalism and religion only subtracted from objective
        truth, so Voltaire freed himself for their influence when he recorded
        history.</string>

    <string name="contempory">- World history became a popular genre in the 20th
        century with universal history. In the 1920s, several best-sellers dealt
        with the history of the world, including surveys The Story of Mankind
        (1921) by Hendrik Willem van Loon and The Outline of History (1918) by
        H.G. Wells. Influential writers who have reached wide audiences include
        H. G. Wells, Oswald Spengler, Arnold J. Toynbee, Pitirim Sorokin, Carroll
        Quigley, Christopher Dawson, and Lewis Mumford. Scholars working the
        field include Eric Voegelin, William Hardy McNeill and Michael Mann.
         With evolving technologies such as dating methods and surveying laser
        technology called LiDAR, contemporary historians have access to new
        information which changes how past civilizations are studied.</string>

    <string name="economics">- ECONOMICS is a social science concerned with the
        production, distribution, and consumption of goods and services. It
        studies how individuals, businesses, governments, and nations make
        choices about how to allocate resources.</string>

    <string name="economics1">- Economics focuses on the actions of human beings, based
        on assumptions that humans act with rational behavior, seeking the
        most optimal level of benefit or utility. The building blocks of
        economics are the studies of labor and trade. Since there are many
        possible applications of human labor and many different ways to
        acquire resources, it is the task of economics to determine which
        methods yield the best results.</string>

    <string name="economics2">- The principle (and problem) of economics is
        that human beings have unlimited wants and occupy a world of limited
        means. For this reason, the concepts of efficiency and productivity
        are held paramount by economists. Increased productivity and a more
        efficient use of resources, they argue, could lead to a higher
        standard of living.</string>

    <string name="economics3">- Despite this view, economics has been
        pejoratively known as the "dismal science," a term coined by Scottish
        historian Thomas Carlyle in 1849. He used it to criticize the liberal
        views on race and social equality of contemporary economists like
        John Stuart Mill, though some commentators suggest Carlyle was
        actually describing the gloomy predictions by Thomas Robert Malthus
        that population growth would always outstrip the food supply.</string>

    <string name="microeconomics">- MICROECONOMICS, focuses on how individual
        consumers and firms make decisions; these individual decision making
        units can be a single person, a household, a business/organization,
        or a government agency. Analyzing certain aspects of human behavior,
        microeconomics tries to explain how they respond to changes in price
        and why they demand what they do at particular price levels.
        Microeconomics tries to explain how and why different goods are
        valued differently, how individuals make financial decisions, and
        how individuals best trade, coordinate, and cooperate with one another
        . Microeconomics\' topics range from the dynamics of supply and demand
        to the efficiency and costs associated with producing goods and
        services; they also include how labor is divided and allocated;
        how business firms are organized and function; and how people approac
        h uncertainty, risk, and strategic game theory.</string>

    <string name="macroeconomics">- MACROECONOMICS studies an overall economy
        on both a national and international level, using highly aggregated
        economic data and variables to model the economy. Its focus can include
        a distinct geographical region, a country, a continent, or even the
        whole world. Its primary areas of study are recurrent economic cycles
        and broad economic growth and development. Topics studied include
        foreign trade, government fiscal and monetary policy, unemployment
        rates, the level of inflation and interest rates, the growth of total
        production output as reflected by changes in the Gross Domestic
        Product (GDP), and business cycles that result in expansions, booms,
        recessions, and depressions. </string>

    <string name="both">- Micro and macroeconomics are intertwined. Aggregate
        macroeconomic phenomena are obviously and literally just the sum total
        of microeconomic phenomena. However these two branches of economics use
        very different theories, models, and research methods, which sometimes
        appear to conflict with each other. Integrating the microeconomics
        foundations into macroeconomic theory and research is a major area of
        study in itself for many economists.</string>

    <string name="macro">- Two of the most common in macroeconomics are MONETARIST
        and KEYNESIAN. Monetarists are a branch of Keynesian economics that argue
        that stable monetary policy is the best course for managing the economy,
        and otherwise often have generally favorable views on free markets as the
        best way to allocate resources. In contrast, other Keynesian approaches
        favor fiscal policy by an activist government in order to manage
        irrational market swings and recessions and believe that markets often
        don\'t work well at allocating resources on their own.</string>

    <string name="indicators">- Economic indicators are reports that detail a
        country\'s economic performance in a specific area. These reports are
        usually published periodically by governmental agencies or private
        organizations, and they often have a considerable effect on stocks,
        fixed income, and forex markets when they are released. They can also
        be very useful for investors to judge how economic conditions will
        move markets and to guide investment decisions.</string>

    <string name="issue">- A contemporary issue refers to an issue that is
        currently affecting people or places and that is unresolved. A
        geographic issue refers to a topic, concern or problem, debate, or
        controversy related to a natural and/or cultural environment, which
        includes a spatial dimension.</string>

    <string name="environmental">- The Philippines are prone to natural disasters, particularly typhoons, floods,
        landslides, volcanic eruptions, earthquakes, and tsunamis, lying as it does astride the
        typhoon belt, in the active volcanic region known as the “Pacific Ring of Fire,” and in the
        geologically unstable region between the Pacific and Eurasian tectonic plates. The
        Philippines also suffers major human-caused environmental degradation aggravated by
        a high annual population growth rate, including loss of agricultural lands, deforestation,
        soil erosion, air and water pollution, improper disposal of solid and toxic wastes, loss of
        coral reefs, mismanagement and abuse of coastal resources, and overfishing.</string>


    <string name="climate">- Recent scientific studies reveal
        that human activities have contributed
        significantly to the increase of
        greenhouse gases in the atmosphere
        that causes climate change.</string>

    <string name="climate1">- The Philippines is a hotspot for
        climate change disasters particularly the
        risk for agriculture and food security due
        to extreme El Nino and severe tropical
        cyclones. The spread of infectious
        diseases are influenced by fluctuations in
        climate variables, temperature, relative
        humidity and rainfall. Sever super
        typhoons like Reming that pummeled the Bicol region in 2006 destroyed at least $90-
        million worth of agricultural products and infrastructure. </string>

    <string name="climate2">- Diseases such as dengue fever, malaria, cholera have increased throughout the
        years. Climate change impacts on coastal zones and marine ecosystems caused
        massive coral bleaching especially in 1998 due to elevated sea temperature and fish
        kills and red tides like the one that occurred in 1992 which was an El Nino period.</string>


    <string name="climate3">- Scientists warned the Philippines could experience famine by 2020, as the
        adverse impact of global warming takes its toll on natural resources. Thousands will be
        displaced from their homes especially in low-lying coastal communities. </string>

    <string name="waste">- The Philippines is looming with
        garbage problems despite the passage
        of the Ecological Solid Waste
        Management Act or the Republic Act
        (RA) 9003.</string>

    <string name="waste1">- 2007 first quarter data from the
        National Solid Waste Management
        Commission shows that there are 677
        open dumpsites, 343 controlled dumps,
        and 21 landfills in the country. An
        additional 307 dump sites are subject for
        closure or rehabilitation plans but without
        definite schedules for enforcement. About 215 additional landfills are being proposed to
        be set up nationwide.</string>

    <string name="waste2">-Environmentalists stress that Republic Act 9003 calls for the adoption of the best
        environmental practices in ecological waste management and explicitly excludes waste
        incineration as an ecological option. These polluting disposal facilities are major sources
        of greenhouse gas emissions to the atmosphere which adds to global warming.
        Landfills and open dumps, according to studies, account for 34 percent of humanrelated methane emissions to the atmosphere, a global warming gas that has 23 times
        more heat-trapping power than carbon dioxide. These landfills and open dumps are
        illegal under RA 9003.  </string>

    <string name="people">- Behavior is a key cultural aspect that is embedded in people’s way of life.
Studying a community’s behavior and introducing new ones requires intensive, longterm, and creative social marketing. This can be done by studying the demographic and
cultural fiber of the community through immersions and capacity building activities.</string>


    <string name="people1">- The Resources, Environment and Economics Center for Studies, Inc.’s (REECS)
2002 study on household waste management systems and the attitudes and behavior
showed that:
</string>

    <string name="people2">- Recognizing the importance of the environment’s immediate recovery and effects
of improper waste management to the Philippines, there is a need for understanding
and reformation of attitudes and concern towards the protection of environment. The
impending garbage crisis can be prevented if we only practice waste segregation at
source, recycling, and composting as what the law requires. An intensive social
marketing program has to be established on a long-term scale within a barangay – the
smallest unit of the local government. </string>

    <string name="politics">POLITICS (from greek POLITIKA, \'affairs of the cities\')
        is the set of activities that are associated with making decisions in groups, or
        other forms of power relations, between individuals, such as the distribution
        of resources or status.</string>

    <string name="politics1">The Philippines is a republic with a presidential
        form of government wherein power is equally divided among its three
        branches: executive, legislative, and judicial. The government seeks
        to act in the best interests of its citizens through this system of
        check and balance.</string>

    <string name="gov">- The Philippines is a republic with a presidential form of
        government wherein power is equally divided among its three branches:
        executive, legislative, and judicial. The government seeks to act in the
        best interests of its citizens through this system of check and balance.
    </string>

    <string name="gov1">- One basic corollary in a presidential system of
        government is the principle of separation of powers wherein legislation
        belongs to Congress, execution to the Executive, and settlement of legal
        controversies to the Judiciary.</string>

    <string name="legislative">- is authorized to make laws, alter, and repeal them
        through the power vested in the Philippine Congress. This institution is
        divided into the Senate and the House of Representatives.</string>
    <string name="legislative1">- The Legislative Branch enacts legislation, confirms
        or rejects Presidential appointments, and has the authority to declare
        war. This branch includes Congress (the Senate and House of Representatives)
        and several agencies that provide support services to Congress.</string>
    <string name="legislative2">- The Senate is composed of 24 Senators who are elected
        at large by the qualified voters of the Philippines.</string>
    <string name="legislative3">- The House of Representatives is composed of about 250
        members elected from legislative districts in the provinces, cities, and
        municipalities, and representatives elected through a party-list system
        of registered national, regional, and sectoral parties or organizations.
    </string>
    <string name="legislative4">- The party-list representatives shall constitute twenty
        per cent of the total number of representatives including those under the party
        list. For three consecutive terms after the ratification of this Constitution,
        one-half of the seats allocated to party-list representatives shall be filled,
        as provided by law, by selection or election from the labor, peasant, urban
        poor, indigenous cultural communities, women, youth, and such other sectors
        as may be provided by law, except the religious sector.</string>

    <string name="executive">- The Executive branch is composed of the President and the
        Vice President who are elected by direct popular vote and serve a term of
        six years. The Constitution grants the President authority to appoint his
        Cabinet. These departments form a large portion of the country’s
        bureaucracy.</string>
    <string name="executive1">- The executive branch carries out and enforces
        laws. It includes the President, Vice President, the Cabinet, executive
        departments, independent agencies, boards, commissions, and committees.
    </string>
    <string name="executive2">- The President leads the country. He or she is the
        head of state, leader of the national government, and Commander-in-Chief
        of all armed forces of the Philippines. The President serves a six-year
        term and cannot be re-elected.</string>
    <string name="executive3">- The Vice President supports the President. If
        the President is unable to serve, the Vice President becomes President.
        He or she also serves a six-year term.</string>
    <string name="executive4">- Cabinet members serve as advisors to the President.
        They include the Vice President and the heads of executive departments.
        Cabinet members are nominated by the President and must be confirmed by
        the Commission of Appointments.</string>

    <string name="judiciary">- The Judicial branch holds the power to settle
        controversies involving rights that are legally demandable and enforceable.
        This branch determines whether or not there has been a grave abuse of
        discretion amounting to lack or excess of jurisdiction on the part and
        instrumentality of the government. It is made up of a Supreme Court and
        lower courts.</string>
    <string name="judiciary1">- The judicial branch interprets the meaning of laws,
        applies laws to individual cases, and decides if laws violate the
        Constitution. The judicial power shall be vested in one Supreme Court
        and in such lower courts as may be established by law.</string>

    <string name="extra">- The Constitution expressly grants the Supreme Court
        the power of Judicial Review as the power to declare a treaty,
        international or executive agreement, law, presidential decree,
        proclamation, order, instruction, ordinance or regulation unconstitutional.
    </string>

    <!--codes for SOCIOLOGY topic college-->
    <string name="sociology">- Sociology is the study of human social relationships and
        institutions. Sociology’s subject matter is diverse, ranging from crime to
        religion, from the family to the state, from the divisions of race and
        social class to the shared beliefs of a common culture, and from social
        stability to radical change in whole societies. Unifying the study of
        these diverse subjects of study is sociology’s purpose of understanding
        how human action and consciousness both shape and are shaped by surrounding
        cultural and social structures.</string>

    <string name="matter">- Sociologists investigate the structure of groups,
        organizations, and societies, and how people interact within these contexts.
    </string>

    <string name="matter1">- All human behavior is social so the subject matter of
        sociology ranges from the intimate family to the hostile mob; from organized
        crime to religious cults; from the divisions of race, gender and social class to
        the shared beliefs of a common culture; and from the sociology of work to the
        sociology of sports.</string>

    <!--codes for roles in society college)-->

    <string name="roles">- We all play certain roles in our society- Social Scientists
        refer to this as status.</string>

    <string name="roles1">- STATUS, is the term used to describe our position within
        an institution.</string>

    <string name="hierarchy">- HIERARCHY, is the ranking system used in any particular
        environment based on authority or power.</string>

    <string name="hierarchy1">- Each position or role requires a certain type of expertise
        which is valued by society.</string>

    <string name="hierarchy2">- In order to distinguish between these rolees people
        are expected to dress and act in a certain way.</string>

    <string name="hierarchy3">- On any given day we can play many different roles in society.</string>

    <!--codes for rules, norms and values-->
    <string name="values">- VALUES, Society carries with it a system of values. A
        particular set of values are assigned to each role. The practitioners of these
        roles are expected to accept and internalize these values.</string>

    <string name="norms">- NORMS, These are rules set out for a particular role
        that are considered standard behaviour (eg. Catholic Priests are expected
        to be celibate).</string>

    <string name="rules">- RULES, These are developed by cultures based on their system
        of values.</string>

    <string name="deviance">- DEVIANCE, Any behaviour that is different from the
        societal norm. It is deviant because we, as a society, do not accept it. Deviance
        can range from simple eccentricities to behaviour that harms society or is
        considered disreputable.</string>

    <!--codes for rehabilitation-->
    <string name="rehabilitation">- Sociology has formed a strong link with the justice system.
    </string>

    <string name="rehabilitation1">- A fundamental component of modern imprisonment is
        rehabilitation, or trying to re-educate and resocialize inmates so that they can grow
        to accept society\'s values and norms.</string>

    <string name="neo">- Based on ideas originally proposed by Karl Marx (1818-1883).</string>
    <string name="neo1">- Marx believed that economic power led to political
        power. This is the key to understanding societies.</string>
    <string name="neo2">- The struggle for economic power means that society is not
        static but ever-changing - social change is the result of a change made to the
        economic system.</string>
    <string name="neo3">- Neo-Marxists believe the economic system creates a rich class
        of owners and a poor class of workers.</string>

    <string name="feminist">- Feminist Theory, focus on sex and gender issues,
        believing that women have traditionally been disadvantaged in societty because
        men have discriminated against them.</string>

    <string name="feminist1">- They believe that men ,have made the decisions in society
        and that they tend to favour men.</string>

    <string name="feminist2">- LIBERAL FEMINISM, Liberal (or BOURGEOIS) Feminism, in
        which the claim of women for equal rights is seen in the context of a general
        opposition to various forms of oppression and discrimination, independently of
        other political convictions. Liberal feminism tends to emphasise social policy to
        open up professional, better-paid and pretigious jobs to women and the elimination
        of laws discriminating against the political, property and social right of women
        (encyclopedia of Mrxism).</string>

    <string name="marxian">- They believe that women\'s unpaid and undervalued
        domestic work has made it possible for undustrial owners to pay lower wages
        to male workers.</string>

    <string name="marxian1">- They also believe that the continuation of lower paid
        jobs has enabled the dominant class (the capitalists) to retains their control.</string>

    <string name="radical">- They believe that their natural childd bearing role has
        to a systematic oppression by men.</string>

    <string name="radical1">- They believe they live in patriarchal society in which men
        dominate most of the institutions and are so entrenched that women cannot
        break in to these fields.</string>

    <string name="socialist">- SOCIALIST FEMINISM, try to separate issues of oppression
        that are the result of patriarchy which is a result of capitalism.</string>


</resources>