<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Agapay</string>

    <string name="about">ABOUT</string>
    <string name="Philippines">The PHILIPPINES are an island group of over 7,500 islands;
        the main islands are Luzon, Mindanao, Mindoro, Leyte, Samar, Negros and Panay.
        Most of the Philippine islands are of volcanic origin. The archipelago is
        situated within the Southeast Asian part of the Pacific Ring of Fire, an area
        of intense volcanic and seismic activities. Along the eastern side of the islands
        runs the Philippine Trench, a submarine trench in the floor of the Philippine Sea. The Galathea
        Depth within the underwater canyon is one of the deepest depths of the ocean at
        10,540m (34,580 feet)</string>

    <string name="MSA">Map of Philippines, Maritime Southeast Asia.</string>

    <string name="LVM">The map shows the main island Luzon, Visayas,
        and Mindanao, other large and small islands, regional capitals,
        major cities, main roads, railroads and major airports.</string>
    <string name="mayon">Mt. Mayon a sacred mountain and an active stratovolcano in the province
        of Albay on the islan of Luzon, Philippines.
        Image: Albert Lozado</string>

    <string name="Area">With a total of 300,000 km(2), the country is about the size
        of Italy or slightly larger than the US state of Arizona.</string>

    <string name="Population">A population of nearly 108 million people (in 2020) making
        the Philippines the world\'s 13th most populous country. The nation\'s capital is Manila,
        located on Luzon island within a densely populated conglomerate of several
        other major cities. Together they form Metro Manila, also known as the National
        Capital Region (NCR). 12.8 million people live in Metro Manila. The country\'s spoken
        languages are Filipino (based on Tagalog) and English.</string>

    <string name="PMSA">The map shows the islands of the Philippines in Maritime
        Southeast Asia. The archipelago lies to the east of the South China Sea and
        west of the Philippine Sea and the western Pacific Ocean. Nearby
        countries are Malaysia in the southwest, Indonesia in the south, Vietnam
        in the west, and Taiwan, and mainland China to the north. The Philippines
        shares maritime borders with China, Indonesia, Japan, Malaysia, Palau,
        Taiwan (ROC), and Vietnam.
    </string>

    <string name="landforms">LANDFORMS - Natural formation of rocks, soil and even dirt
        found on earth. They come in different shapes and sizes.</string>

    <string name="landforms1">- Theses place are also the tourist spot that foreigners
        and even filipino visit during summer.</string>

    <string name="mountain">- It is a place that is much higher than the
        land around it. Some mountains very steep and around to climb.</string>

    <string name="apo">- At 2,956 meters above sea level, Mt. Apo (or "master" or
        "grandchild" in Filipino) is the highest mountain in the Philippines. Scale
        the summit and be rewarded with majestic views of Davao to the northeast,
        Digos City to the southeast, and Kidapawan to the West.</string>

    <string name="apo1">- MT. APO was declared a national park in 1934 by then PRESIDENT
        MANUEL L. QUEZON, and rightly so. Apart from lush forests, it is home
        to over 272 bird species, the most notable of which is the endangered
        Philippine eagle.</string>

    <string name="dulang">- The second highest mountain the Philippines is home to the
        Talaandig tribe, who consider Mt. Dulang-Dulang a sacred place.</string>

    <string name="dulang1">- The tribes folk live side by side with an amazing variety
        of wildlife - deer, flying lemurs, monkeys, and bats, to name a few.</string>

    <string name="dulang2">- Start your journey on trails lined with pine trees and then
        navigate through jungles that take you back in time. Be rewarded with a view of
        Mt. Apo and the entire Kitanglad range at the peak.</string>

    <string name="pulag">- MT.PULAG is Luzon\'s highest peak. This national park is home
        to the Ibalos, Kilanguya, Kankana-eys, Karao, Ifugaos, and the Ilocanos.</string>

    <string name="pulag1">- It is a popular destination among mountaineers for its amazing
        sea of clouds and views of the Milky Way galaxy right before the sun rises.</string>

    <string name="pulag2">- Due to a fire that destroyed more than 5 hectares of grassland,
        Mt. Pulag is closed to trekkers until further  notice.</string>

    <string name="kitanglad">- Legend has it that Mt.Kitanglad was named after a great
        flood submerged the land and only the mountain\'s peak, which was the size of a blade
        of lemon grass (TANGLAD in Filipino) was visible.</string>

    <string name="kitanglad1">- Mountaineers might be surprised to learn that Mt.Kitanglad
        is a communications center. But don\'t be put off by its seeming modernity. The
        challenging trails, beautiful views, and the richness of its biodiversity make the journey
        worth it.</string>

    <string name="tabayoc">- Tabayoc, in the native tongue, means (BASIN), which may refer
        to the four lakes surrounding it: Lake Tabeo, Ambulalakao, Iculus, and Detapnaco.</string>

    <string name="tabayoc1">- A significant portion of Mt. Tabayoc’s trail is known as the
        “Monkey Trail” – trekkers would have to climb over boulders, swing from one branch
        to another, and hang on to vines to move forward.</string>

    <string name="tabayoc2">- If you’ve ever wondered what it would be like to be in Tarzan’s
        shoes (or, um, loincloth), climbing the second highest mountain in Luzon would be your
        chance to find out.</string>

    <string name="kalatungan">- Mt. Kalatungan (or “praying mantis eggs” in the native tongue)
        is classified as a potentially active volcano and is considered as one of the most
        challenging climbs in the country. In keeping with local traditions, mountaineers
        perform a ritual sacrifice prior to the climb.</string>

    <string name="piapayungan">- Mt. Piapayungan remains to be one of Mindanao\'s most elusive peaks</string>

    <string name="ragang">- Mt. Ragang, also known as the Blue Mountain, is the highest
        point in Lanao Del Sur. Emerge from the ethereal mossy forest and be rewarded with
        a view of Lake Lanao as well as towns of Maguindanao, Lanao del Sur, and Cotabato.</string>

    <string name="maagnaw">- Mt.Maagnaw is the third highest peak in the Kitanglad range
        and the 8th highest mountain in the country. If you\'ve conquered Mt.Dulang-Dulang and
        Mt.Kitanglad, this should also be on your list. The views at the summit are truly
        breathtaking.</string>

    <string name="timbak">- If you\'re on a mission to summit the 10 highest mountains
        in the Philippines, Mt.Timbak - 9th on the list - said to be the easiest to complete.</string>

    <string name="timbak1">- Get a glimpse of the local way of life along the way, and take
        photos of the three crosses at the summit. Mountaineers usually plan a day
        hike to Mt.Timbak from Baguio. Its environs are also a playground for trail runners.</string>


    <string name="volcano">- It is a landform that has a small opening on top where hot
        rocks or lava come out when it erupts.</string>

    <string name="volcano1">- VOLCANOES in the Philippines, (15 in CENTRAL
        PHILIPPINES) ALTO, BILIRAN, CABALIAN, CANCAJANG, CANLAON, CUERNOS DE NEGROS,
        HINGATUNGAN, ILIHAN, LOBI, MAHAGNAO, MANDALAGAN, MARIPIPI, NELANGAAPAN, PACDAHAUAN,
        SILAY. (33 in LUZON ISLAND) AMBALATUNGAN, AMORONG, ANILAO HILL, ARAYAT, BANAHAW, BINULUAN,
        BULUSAN, CAGUA, CARILAO, CONE-CULASI, CORREGIDOR, DAGIT-DAGITAN, GATE MOUNTAINS,
        IRIGA, ISAROG, LABO, LAGUNA, MAKILING, MALEPUNYO, MALINAO, MALINDIG, MARIVELES,
        MASARAGA, MAYON, NATIB, PANAY, PATOC, PINATUBO, POCDOL MOUNATINS, SAN PABLO,
        SANGAY, SANTO TOMAS, TAAL. (20 in MINDANAO) AMPIRO, APO, BALATUKAN, BALUT,
        BLIT, HIBOK-HIBOK, IMBING, KALADIS, KALATUNGAN, KITABUD, LATUKAN, LEONARD RANGE,
        MAKATURING, MALINDANG, MATUTUM, MUSUAN, PACO, PARKER, QUEZON, RAGANG. (6 in NORTH LUZON)
        BABUYAN CLARO, CAMIGUIN DE BABUYANES, DIDICAS, IRAYA, MATAREM. (1 in SULU ISLAND)
        JOLO.</string>

    <string name="volcano2">- There are 53 active volcanoes in the Philippines. The
        Philippines belong to the Pacific Ring of Fire where the oceanic Philippine plate
        and several smaller microplates are subducting along the Philippines Trench
        to the E, and the Luzon, Sulu and several other small Trenches to the W.</string>

    <string name="volcano3">According to the Philippine Institute of Volcanology and Seismology
        (PHIVOLCS),at least 24 of these volcanoes are active or potentially active, while
        the rest are dormant. Based on documented eruptions over the years, the six most
        active volcanoes are:</string>

    <string name="plain">- It is low, flat and wide landform. It has many towns and
        cities and it is where most people build their houses. This is suitable for
        planting various crops like rice and corn. usually, people build their homes
        and establish settlements with governing bodies in the plain. The widest plain is
        in Central Luzon. It is otherwise known as the Rice Granary of the country. In
        the Visayas, the plains of Panay and Negros are bountiful. in Mindanao, the
        wide plains are found in Cotabato, Davao, and Agusan.</string>

    <string name="plain1">- There are 10 biggest islands in the Philippines. These
        are the following: Luzon, Mindanao, Samar, Negros, Palawan, Panay, Mindoro,
        Leyte, Cebu, and Bohol.</string>

    <string name="plain2">* CENTRAL LUZON region, also known as Region 3, comprises the
        largest plain of the Philippines, it is called most of the country\'s rice supply. It
        was the third largest region in terms of population size amidst the 16 regions
        in the Philippines, containing 10.50 percent of the 76.5 million human beings of the
        country as recorded in Census 2000.</string>

    <string name="hill">- It is lower and smaller than a mountain. It is easier to
        climb than a mountain.</string>

    <string name="banati">- It is a hill located in Bool, Tagbilaran City. This hill
        commands a scenic view overlooking vast Bohol Sea, Islands of Mindanao,
        Negros and Siquijor and the strait of Panglao Island. Elevation is 146 above sea level.</string>

    <string name="bangan">- It is a protected area of the Philippines located in
        the municipality of Bayombong, Nueva Vizcaya in Cagayan Valley. The park
        covers an area of 13.90 hectares. It was declared a national park in 1995
        by virtue of Republic Act No. 7954.</string>

    <string name="bangan1">- The park is a historic and cultural landmark of Nueva
        Viscaya, being the site of the first mass in the province in the province in
        1739 officiated by Father Pedro Freire. The event also marked the founding
        of the municipality of Bayombong. The park is also the site of the annual
        "Stations of the Cross" staged by the local Catholic church during the Lenten
        season using live actors depicting the last moments leading to Jesus Christ\'s
        crucifixion. It is also an ideal year-round destination for hiking enthusiasts
        with the observation deck commanding a great view of the expanse of the surrounding
        valley formed by the Caraballo and Cordillera Central mountains.</string>

    <string name="cassamata">- It is a protected area of the Philippines located in the
        municipality of Bangued, Abra in te Cordillera Administrative Region. The park
        covers an area of 57 hectares (140 acres) and was declared a protected area in
        1974.</string>

    <string name="cassamata1">- Its location in the southern limits of Bangued municipality
        by the Ilocos Sur-Abra road affords easy access to its residents. The hill itself
        is an easy climb via a winding road or on foot by concrete stairways. Visitors
        are rewarded with panoramic views of the small town below as well as the whole
        expanse of the Abra River valley flanked by the Cordillera Central and Ilocos
        mountain ranges. The 990-meter (3,248 feet) tall Mount Banti Goolong (also
        called SLEEPING BEAUTY mountain by locals) is especially impresive from Victoria
        Park located in the summit of the hill. In addition to the park and mountain
        trails, Cassamata Hill also provides recreational facilities such as swimming
        pool, a hotel and an amphitheater. The park is also the site of a water reservoir
        and a shrine to the Virgin Mary.</string>

    <string name="chocolate">- Are a geological formation in the Bohol province of the
        Philippines. There are at least 1,260 hills but there may be as many as 1,776
        hills spread over an area of more than 50 square kilometers (20 sq mi). They
        are covered in green grass that turns brown during the dry season, hence the name.</string>

    <string name="chocolate1">- The CHOCOLATE HILLS is a famous tourist attraction
        of Bohol. They are featured in the provincial flag and seal to symbolize the
        abundance of natural attractions in the province. They are in the Philippine
        Tourism Authority\'s list of tourist destination in the Philippines; they have
        been declared the country\'s third National Geological Monument and proposed for
        inclusion in the UNESCO World Heritage.</string>

    <string name="himontagon">- Are a group of hills in Loay, Bohol, Philippines,
        about 20 kilometers from the Tagbilaran City.</string>

    <string name="lignon">- It is a prominent hill in the city of Legazpi, some
        3 kilometers west of its downtown port area in Albay, Philippines. The
        summit rises to about 512 feet (156 meters), overlooking the Mayon Volcano
        to the northwest and the entire city and Albay Gulf to the east. The whole
        site is managed by the city and provincial government, and has been designed
        as a Nature Park.</string>

    <string name="lignon1">- Lignon hill is a prehistoric cinder cone near the foot
        of Mayon, ssome 12 kilometers south-southeast of the volcano\'s summit. It is
        mainly composed of dolerite and basaltic volcanic rocks. Except for Mayon
        Volcano, it is the highest point in the city situated next to the Legazpi
        Airport in barangay 41 (Bogtong) near the city\'s border with the municipality
        of Daraga. It hosts the Mayon Volcano Observatory, the central monitoring
        station of the Philippine Institute of Volcanology and Seismology built in 1989.</string>

    <string name="manduyog">- It is a religious sanctuary located at the Aklan State
        University, Banga, Aklan, the Philippines. Today, Manduyog Hill attracts visitors
        not only within the province but even from other provinces in the country.
        During fiesta day every September 14 and the Lenten season, throngs of
        multitudes go up the Hill not only the religious fervor, but also by the
        captivating spell of its magical tranquility.</string>

    <string name="pedro">- Also known as PC Hill or Tantawan, is a hill in Cotabato
        City, Philippines.</string>

    <string name="pedro1">- The name of hill, Pedro Colin Hill was named after Peter
        the Apostle (or San Pedro) by the Spaniards in the 1800s, during the time when
        the Spanish began exploring South Central Mindanao. COLINA means hill in Spanish,
        hence Pedro Colina Hill\'s name is tautological or redundant. The hill is also
        traditionally known as Tantawan, which meanas EXTENSIVE VEIW.</string>

    <string name="plateau">- A plateau is a flat stretch of land on top os a mountain.
        This suitable for tending animals as the temperature here is cool. It is also
        ideal for plants that do not need much water. The bid plateaus around the country
        are found in the Mountain Province, Benguet, Ifugao, and Kalinga-Apayao in Luzon.</string>

    <string name="mountainranges">- It is a chain of mountains bondered by higlands
        or separated from other mountains by passes or valleys.</string>

    <string name="apotalomo">- Also known as Mount Talomo) or Talomo Mountain Range
        is a mountain Range located in the province of Davao del Sur and Cotabato in
        the island of Mindanao Philippines. The highest peak on the range is Mount Apo
        9,692 ft. (2,954 m) it is the highest mountain in the Philippines. Mount Talomo 8,773 ft
        (2,674 m) is one of the top 15 highest mountain in the Philippines. In terms of climbing
        difficulty, it is rated with a 7/9 difficulty and has a 2-4 trail class.</string>

    <string name="caraballo">- It is a mountain range in the central part of Luzon island
        in the Philippines, situated between the Cordillera Central and Sierra Madre
        mountain ranges. The mountains serve as the location off the headways of the
        Cagayan River, the longest in the country.</string>

    <string name="central">- It is the longest and largest mountain range in the island
        of Panay and Western Visayas in the Philippines. With a total lenght of 170 km (105 miles)
        long north-south and 34 km (21 miles) width east-west. It is famous for its
        diverse flora and fauna. Located through the western Panay, started from Ibajay, Aklan
        to the north and Aniniy, Antique southern tip to the south.</string>

    <string name="peninsula">- A peninsula is a substantial portion of land that extends
        from the mainland and has water on three sides. It can be formed by rising or
        falling sea level that may expose or cover portions of land to form a peninsula.
        An uplift or fall of landmass may also help to form a peninsula. A separation
        of Landmasses over millions of years can create a peninsula.</string>

    <string name="bataan">- The peninsula faces the South china Sea to the west and
        Subic Bay to the north-west, and encloses Manila Bay to the east.</string>

    <string name="bondoc">- commonly known as BONPEN, is located in the southeastern
        part of Quezon Province in Calabarzon Region, southern part of Luzon Island,
        Philippines. The peninsula consists of 12 municipalities.</string>

    <string name="calatagan">- Calatagan comprises the Calatagan Peninsula between the
        South China Sea and Balayan Bay. The peninsula\'s near white sand beaches are
        well known vacation and leisures sites. The word CALATAGAN is taken from the
        Tagalog word LATAG and is closely associated with KAPATAGAN, which means a vast portion
        of flat and lying between the hills and mountais.</string>

    <string name="valley">- It is a type landform. A valley is a lower part in the land,
        between two higher parts which might be hills or mountains. Valleys often start as a
        downward fold between two upwards folds in the surface of the Earth, and sometimes
        as a rift valley.</string>

    <string name="valley1">- A valley is made deeper by a stream of water or a river
        as it flows from the high land to the lower land, and into a lake or sea. Some
        valleys are made by GLACIERS  which are slow-moving rivers of ice.</string>

    <string name="allah">- It is a large valley of the Allah River in the provinces of
        South Cotabato and Sultan Kudarat on the island of Mindanao, Philippines. It
        is formed by the Roxas-Matulas Range in the north and the Daguma Mountain Range
        in the south.</string>

    <string name="cagayan">- Cagayan Valley is the second largest Philippine administrative
        region by land area. Most of the land area is situated on the valley between the Cordilleras
        and the Sierra Madre mountain ranges. The eponymous Cagayan River, the country\'s
        largest and second longest, runs through the region and flows from the Caraballo
        Mountains and ends at Aparri.</string>

    <string name="davao">- The province was formerly known as COMPOSTELA VALLEY, from
        its inception until December 2019, when a plebiscite ratified the law that
        proposed to rename the province to Davao de Oro.</string>

    <string name="dewil">- located in the northernmost part of Palawan, an island province
        of the Philippines that is located in the Mimaropa region, is an archaeological site
        composed of thousands of artifacts and features.</string>

    <string name="population">In statistics, a population is the entire pool from which a
        statistical sample is drawn. A population may refer to an entire group of people,
        objects, events, hospital visits, or measurements. A population can thus be said
        to be an aggregate observation of subjects grouped together by a common feature.</string>

    <string name="population1">A population can be defined by any number of characteristics
        within a group that statisticians use to draw conclusions about the subjects in
        a study. A population can be vague or specific. Examples of population
        (defined VAGUELY) include the number of newborn babies in North America,
        total number of tech startups in Asia, average height of all CFA candidates
        in the world, mean weight of U.S taxpayers and so on.</string>

    <string name="ph">- The current population of the PHILIPPINES is 110,416,174
        as of Thursday, January 28, 2021, based on Worldometer elaboration of the
        latest United Nations data.</string>

    <string name="ph1">- The Philippines 2020 poulation is estimated at 109,581,078
        people at mid year according to UN data.</string>

    <string name="ph2">- The Philippines population is equavalent to 1.41% of
        the total world population.</string>

    <string name="ph3">- The Philippines ranks number 13 in the list of countries
        (and dependencies) by population.</string>

    <string name="ph4">- The population density in the Philippines is 368 per Km2
        (952 people per mi2).</string>
    <string name="ph5">- The total land area is 298,170 Km2 (115,124 sq. miles).</string>
    <string name="ph6">- 47.5% of the population is urban (52,008,603 people i 2020).</string>
    <string name="ph7">- The median age in the Philippines is 25.7 years.</string>

    <string name="pdc">The Philippines is not a developed country. The nation falls
        behind on every one of the most common metrics used by economist to determine
        development status. The Philippines\' per capita gross domestic product (GDP),
        Human Development Index (HDI) and life expectancy sit well below the thresholds
        for developed country status. Moreover, the country\'s infant mortality rate is
        very high, its industrialization is minimal, and many of its citizens lack
        access to quality health care and higher education.</string>

    <string name="pdc1">As of 2016, per capita GDP in the Philippines is $7,358, well below
        any accepted minimum for developed country status. The country\'s latest HDI is
        0.66. Its infant mortality rate 22 per 1,000 live births and its life expectancy
        is 69 years.</string>

    <string name="pdc2">The Philippines is very much a developing country, and it has a
        long way to go to reach developed status.</string>

    <string name="manufacturing">- MANUFACTURING comprises more than half of the Philippine\'s
        industrial sector and accounts for almost a quarter of the country\'s Gross
        Domestic Product (GDP). From an annual growth rate of 5.4% in 2012, the
        manufacturing sector grew by 10.5% in 2013 and 8.1% in 2014</string>

    <string name="tourism">TOURISM is an important sector for Philippine economy. In
        2019, the travel and tourism industry contributed 12.7% to the country\'s GDP.
        Philippines is an archipelagic country composed of 7,641 islands with 82 provinces
        divided in 17 regions.</string>

    <string name="bpo">As a prime knowledge process outsourcing destination, the Philippines\'
        KPO sector thrives and stays as part of the country\'s major contributor
        to its GDP. In fact, as per the Information Technology and Business Process Management
        (IT-BPM) Roadmap 2022, the demand for mid-skill and high-skill jobs will take
        46% and 27% of IT-BPM careers, respectively. This proves there is more to
        come for the future of the knowledge process outsourcing industry.</string>

    <string name="infrastructure">The logistics industry remains a significant and growing segment
        of the Philippine economy due to commerce and infrastructure developments.
        In 2019, the transportation and storage summed up to USD 13 billion and has accounted
        for around 4% of the Philippines\' GDP over the last five years.</string>

    <string name="agribusiness">AGRIBUSINESS refers to agriculture-related activities that
        put farmers, processors, distributors, and consumers within a system that produces,
        transport, markets, and distributes agricultural products.</string>

    <string name="philippines">- Is an archipelagic country in Southeast Asia. Situated
        in the western Pacific Ocean, it consists of about 7,641 islands that are
        broadly categorized under three main geographical divisions from north to
        south: Luzon, Visayas, Mindanao. The capital city of the Philippines is
        MANILA and the most populous city is QUEZON CITY, both within the single
        urban area of Metro Manila.</string>
    <string name="philippines1">- The Philippines\' position as an island country on the
        Pacific RING OF FIRE and close to the equator makes the country prone to earthquakes
        and typhoons. The country has a variety of natural resources and a globally significant
        level of biodiversity. The Philippines has an area of around 300,000 km2
        (120,000 sq mi) with a population of around 109 million people. As of 2020,
        it is the 8th-most populated country in the world. Multiple ethnicities and
        cultures are found throughout the islands.</string>

</resources>